A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Ozzie G. Simmons FA679
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Population Program, Office Files of Ozzie G. Simmons
1975-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Simmons, Ozzie G.
Ford Foundation
FA679
1.31 Cubic Feet
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Arrangement
As received.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Scope and Contents
Includes but not limited to: correspondence; reports; program planning, review and evaluation files; budget files and seminar records.
Biographical / Historical
Ozzie Simmons (1919-1988) was a sociologist and anthropologist who worked for more than ten years at the Ford Foundation. Simmons started at the Foundation as a Program Advisor in the Latin America and the Caribbean, Chile Program. He then moved to the Population Program as a Program Officer. After that assignment, he worked for several years in the Asia and the Pacific, Southeast Asia Program where he was a Program Officer and then an Associate Representative/Program Officer. Simmons returned to the Population Program for a few years before he left the Foundation.
Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, Simmons worked as a lecturer and researcher at several institutions including the Smithsonian Institution, Harvard University, the University of Colorado, and Brandeis University. The American Psychiatric Association awarded him the Hofheimer Prize in 1962.
Simmons completed his undergraduate education at Northwestern University and earned master's and doctoral degrees from Harvard University. After he left the Ford Foundation, he joined the Fordham University Hispanic Research Center. Simmons died in 1988.
- Asian Trip Observations, 1978 October-November (Box 1)
- Data Analysis Workshop, 1978 (Box 1)
- El Colegio de Mexico Evaluation Report, 1977 October (Box 1)
- Family Health and Population in Nigeria, 1979 (Box 1)
- Health/Nutrition/Population Activities in Indonesia, 1980 (Box 1)
- Indonesia, 1980 (Box 1)
- International Division Staff Meeting on Women's Programs, 1980 (Box 1)
- International Year of the Child, 1979 (Box 1)
- Korten, Frances -- Program Paper and Memoranda Re: Philippines Public Works Project, 1978 (Box 1)
- Mexico -- Ford Foundation -- Migration Program, 1979 (Box 1)
- Mexico Trip Report, 1979 March 20 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Memoranda, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
- Nicaragua Trip Notes, 1979 (Box 1)
- Peru -- AMIDEP and INANDEP, 1980 (Box 1)
- Population and Integrated Programs, 1981 (Box 1)
- Population Assistance by Major Donors, 1979 (Box 1)
- Population Center Foundation (PREPF), 1975 (Box 1)
- Population Council Evaluation, 1979 (Box 1)
- Population Office Budget, 1979 May 18 (Box 1)
- Population Office Budget Recommendations FY 1978-1979, 1977 (Box 1)
- Population Office Program Review and Funding Request FY 1980-1981, 1979 July (Box 1)
- Population Office Review, 1980 September 30 (Box 1)
- Population Program, 1979 (Box 1)
- Research Competition in Reproductive Science, 1979 (Box 1)
- Rural Resources and Development, undated (Box 1)
- Seminar on Regional Fertility and Development, 1979 (Box 1)
- Yaoude Workshop on Data Processing in the Social Sciences, 1978 (Box 1)